<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<conversations>

	<conversation ID="Crowsong" Load="Merge">
		
		<node ID="Swords" Load="Merge">
			<choice Target="SeenSven" IfHaveState="Sibs_Garden_SvenSeen" Priority="10">That one is no cord -- I have reasons to believe he survived.</choice>
		</node>	
  
  		<node ID="SeenSven" Inherits="Welcome">
			A thread unwoven, to what consequence? I am here, he is there, and that is enough.
		</node>
  
	</conversation>
  
  
	<conversation ID="Sibs_Garden_Cartographer" >
		
		<start ID="Welcome" Inherits="DefaultChoices">
		
			<text IfFinishedQuest="Sibs_Garden_MainQuest" Priority="-1">
				{{emote|*Mudokah =verb:show= you =pronouns.possessive= latest map.*}}
				
				Always a pleasure to see you, =player.formalAddressTerm=. Sit for a while, will you?
			</text>
			<text IfHaveActiveQuest="Sibs_Garden_MainQuest" Priority="-1">
				{{emote|*The cartographer =verb:beam= at your approach.*}}
				
				Oh, it is you! Have you found out more about the lost garden yet?
			</text>
			<text IfNotHaveQuest="Sibs_Garden_MainQuest" Priority="-1">
				{{emote|*=pronouns.Subjective= =verb:phase:afterpronoun= back into reality, pushing horn-rimmed glasses up =pronouns.possessive= nose.*}}
				
				Ah! What can I help you with?
			</text>
		</start>

		<node ID="DefaultChoices">
			<choice Target="Debrief" IfHaveActiveQuest="Sibs_Garden_MainQuest" IfFinishedQuestStep="Sibs_Garden_MainQuest~Solve">Mudokah! I come with news of the lost garden.</choice>
			<choice Target="AboutYou">What do you do here in Kyakukya?</choice>
			<choice Target="Work" IfNotHaveQuest="Sibs_Garden_MainQuest">Can I help you with any work?</choice>
			<choice Target="Map">I could use one of your maps, actually.</choice>
			<choice Target="End">I will tell you of my travels later. In the meantime, live and drink.</choice>
		</node>			
		
		<node ID="AboutYou" Inherits="Welcome">
			<text>
				Quite simple, really! I map out my surroundings, and trade knowledge with locals. This quaint mushroom village is just the latest stop of my journey!
			</text>
		</node>	
		
		<node ID="Map" Inherits="Welcome">
			<text>
				Well, I am always open to trading -- if you've got the freshwater, that is.
			</text>
		</node>			
		
		<node ID="Work">
			<text>
			{{emote|*=pronouns.Subjective= nearly =verb:jump:afterpronoun= at the mention of offered help.*}}
			
			You most certainly can! You're a seasoned traveler, aren't you?	
			</text>
			<choice Target="Brief1">I have traveled Qud far and wide. I will handle whatever you throw my way.</choice>
			<choice Target="Brief1">As long as it is not too far away...</choice>
		</node>

		<node ID="Brief1">
			<text>
			{{emote|*=pronouns.Subjective= =verb:wave:afterpronoun= a hand dismissively.*}}
			
			Well, anyway, I'm sure you will do *just fine*. Say, in your travels, have you ever heard of a garden in the northern part of Qud? Gesh? Geth? Gefh? A name along those lines...	
			</text>
			<choice Target="Brief2">Once or twice maybe -- nothing more than tall tales, and never heard of any precise location.</choice>
			<choice Target="Brief2">Never heard that name before.</choice>
		</node>

		<node ID="Brief2">
			<text>	
			Precisely! See, I once came across an ancient map -- covered in discrepancies, mind you -- that did display a strange circle marking that garden, right by the mountain range, deep in the rubber trees that have been sprouting lately. I need you to venture there, and discover everything you can about the place. Be careful though: I've heard many accounts of travelers never finding their way out of those strange woods.	
			</text>
			<choice Target="End" StartQuest="Sibs_Garden_MainQuest">Travel to the rubber orchard, find the mysterious garden, learn what I can and get back. Sounds simple enough; I am on my way.</choice>
			<choice Target="End">I need to think about it. For now, live and drink.</choice>
		</node>

		<node ID="Debrief">
			<text>
			{{emote|*=pronouns.Possessive= eyes go wide behind the thick-rimmed glasses.*}}
			
			You actually went there! And you came back, too! You must tell me everything about it.
			</text>
			<choice Target="Reward">Certainly. See, there was this underground botanical facility... {{W|*recount your travel to the lost garden*}}</choice>
		</node>

		<node ID="Reward">
			<text>
			{{emote|*Once your tale is over, =pronouns.subjective= =verb:set:afterpronoun= down =pronouns.possessive= notes.*}}
			
			That was quite the trek! I cannot thank you enough, but perhaps I can make it worth your while. Those boots have never failed me, and I'm thinking you would put them to good use -- they are, ironically enough, made from the same rubber as those trees you found your way through.
			</text>
			<choice Target="End" CompleteQuestStep="Sibs_Garden_MainQuest~Debrief" FinishQuest="Sibs_Garden_MainQuest">
				<text>I will make sure to put them to good use. Live and drink, mapmaker.</text>
				<part Name="ReceiveItem" Blueprints="Sibs_Garden_RubberBoots" />
			</choice>
		</node>		

	</conversation>
     
  
	<conversation ID="Sibs_Garden_Computer">
		
		<start ID="Welcome" Inherits="DefaultChoices">
			<text>
				UPTIME COUNT OVERFLOWED.
				
				ACCESS PERMISSIONS RECALIBRATED FOR NEW BASIC USER.
				
				[... I AM AWAITING COMMAND ...]
				
				{{emote|*A keyboard covered in glyphs lets you input your own answers to the mainframe.*}}
			</text>
		</start>

		<node ID="DefaultChoices">
			<choice Target="AboutYou">WHO ARE YOU?</choice>
			<choice Target="AboutPlace">WHAT IS THIS PLACE?</choice>
			<choice Target="Map" IfHaveActiveQuest="Sibs_Garden_MainQuest" IfNotFinishedQuestStep="Sibs_Garden_MainQuest~Solve">HOW COME THIS PLACE IS IN RUINS AND NOT DISPLAYED ON MAPS?</choice>			
			<choice Target="AboutTroll">DO YOU NOT MIND THE FACT A TROLL SET UP SHOP NEARBY?</choice>
			<choice Target="End">EXIT.</choice>
		</node>
  
		<node ID="AboutYou" Inherits="Welcome">
			<text>
				I AM GESHTINANNA, KEEPER OF ABUNDANCE. HOWEVER MUCH YOU TAKE, YOU ARE ASKED TO GIVE BACK TENFOLD.
			</text>
		</node>  
  
		<node ID="AboutPlace" Inherits="Welcome">
			<text>
				A STRONGHOLD OF PLENTY: ROOTS AND SEEDS, STOCKPILED FOR THE FUTURE.
				
				[!!! I AM DETECTING A PARTIAL BREACH !!!]
				
				YOU ARE RECOMMENDED TO TAKE ACTION TO PREVENT CROSS-POLLINATION.
			</text>
		</node>    
  
 		<node ID="AboutTroll" Inherits="Welcome">
			<text>
				EATERS DID NOT FASHION ME TO CARE FOR ZOOLOGICAL LIFE WITHIN THESE HALLS. 
			</text>
		</node>   

  		<node ID="Map">
			<text>
				THE SOIL SHAKES AND OPENS A SKYWARD EYE. FIND SOLACE IN THAT ANSWER FOR I HAVE NONE OTHER. 
			</text>
			<choice Target="Map2">I SEE. WHAT ABOUT MAPS? WHY IS THIS PLACE NOT BETTER KNOWN?</choice>
		</node>

  		<node ID="Map2">
			<text>
				SOME OTHER TRAVELER CAME BEFORE AND LEFT SAYING THEY WOULD SPREAD WORD OF THIS PLACE. 
				
				I LACK DATA TO ANSWER THE REST OF THE INQUIRY.
				
				[... I AM FORMULATING AN HYPOTHESIS ...]
				
				PERHAPS MEMORY IS AKIN TO PLANT LIFE: BOTH REQUIRE WATERING, LEST THEY WITHER. YOU ARE THE FIRST TO HAVE COME HERE SINCE THEN.
			</text>
			<choice Target="End" CompleteQuestStep="Sibs_Garden_MainQuest~Solve">THIS FITS HOW DIFFICULT THAT PLACE IS TO ACCESS. THANK YOU. EXIT.</choice>
		</node>  		
  
	</conversation>  
	
  
  	<conversation ID="Sibs_Garden_Troll">
		
		<start ID="Welcome" Inherits="DefaultChoices">
			<text>
				{{emote|*The massive troll looks down at you, brandishing the frond =pronouns.objective= =verb:keep:afterpronoun= planted in a small enameled cup.*}}
				
				You! We are trading now.
			</text>
		</start>

		<node ID="DefaultChoices">
			<choice Target="ChillTroll">You do not seem like the other trolls I have met upstairs.</choice>
			<choice Target="AboutPlace">Do you know what this place is?</choice>
			<choice Target="Plant">That plant you carry around. Are you a guardian for the Consortium?</choice>
			<choice Target="NoTrade">What if I don't want to trade?</choice>
			<choice Target="End">I am done trading. Live and drink, unexpected merchant.</choice>
		</node>	

		<node ID="AboutPlace" Inherits="Welcome">
			<text>
				My shelter! You are being careful behind those doors -- the walls flicker and want to talk.
			</text>
		</node>

		<node ID="ChillTroll" Inherits="Welcome">
			<text>
				Ah, yes! Budded from my flesh. Foals are restless, but peace is with me now. Storied relics are best traded for than stolen, see?
			</text>
		</node>
		
		<node ID="Plant" Inherits="Welcome">
			<text>
				{{emote|*The troll gently strokes a budding leaf.*}}
				
				Ne is not a member of the Consortium yet! Once growth has stretched nir foliage, ne will be.
			</text>
		</node>
				
		<node ID="NoTrade" Inherits="Welcome">
			<text>
				You do not understand. We *are* trading now -- words, air, maybe water.
			</text>
		</node>
  
	</conversation>
  
  
	<conversation ID="Sibs_Garden_Sven" >
		
		<start ID="Welcome" Inherits="DefaultChoices">
			<text>
				{{emote|*The hermit =verb:look= up at you from =pronouns.possessive= sitting position, rubbing =pronouns.possessive= bad leg.*}}
				
				Hmm? A traveler? That is an unusual sight. Come share the shade, =player.formalAddressTerm=.
			</text>
		</start>

		<node ID="DefaultChoices">
			<choice Target="AboutPlace">What is this place?</choice>
			<choice Target="AboutYou">I was not expecting to find someone so remote from nearby villages.</choice>
			<choice Target="Cucumbers">I have never seen so many cucumbers in one place...</choice>
			<choice Target="End">I must go -- live and drink.</choice>
		</node>
  
 		<node ID="AboutPlace" Inherits="Welcome">
			<text>
				A forgotten place for forgotten things. The rubber trees seldom let people approach, and most avoid it altogether -- no game to hunt, no spoils to claim. Nothing but peace and the creeping vines.
			</text>
			<choice Target="Hole" Priority="10">What about that chasm there? Where does it lead?</choice>
		</node>
  		
		<node ID="Hole" Inherits="Welcome">
			<text>
				Below. Mind that you are equipped for adversity, only the very bottom lends itself to friendly conversations.
			</text>
		</node>
   
   		<node ID="AboutYou" Inherits="Welcome">
			<text>
				And you have not. I am noone worth remembering, and have shed my name where I once laid. Hindsun will see you on your way soon enough, leaving here the memory of our meeting.
			</text>
			<choice Target="YouAreSven" IfHaveState="Sibs_Garden_CrowsongSeen" Priority="10">Your hands flew in remembrance of twin swords, I wager. I have seen a snapjaw in Kyakukya where once a great hunter stood -- word is you died, but here you are!</choice>
		</node>	 

		<node ID="YouAreSven" Inherits="Welcome">
			<text>
				{{emote|*The hermit closes =pronouns.possessive= eyes for an instant.*}}
				
				Whoever you are thinking of, =player.formalAddressTerm=, they are long dead.
			</text>
		</node>
		 
		<node ID="Cucumbers" Inherits="Welcome">Z
			<text>
				{{emote|*A dry chuckle escapes =pronouns.possessive= lips.*}}
				
				Clever fronds! Turning spoilwater into fruit, now that is a skill many wish they possessed.
			</text>
		</node> 
  
	</conversation>
	
  
</conversations>